Guide to the Robert Wilbar Wilson Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Robert Wilbar Wilson papers
1912-1975
MS 1900
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2
(2 boxes)
The papers comprise correspondence, subject files, photographs, and memorabilia documenting aspects of Robert Wilbar Wilson's student years at Yale, his military service, and post-war business endeavors.
Wilson, Robert W. (Robert Wilbar), 1893-1975
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Charlotte G. Currier, 2007.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The papers are arranged by topic and alphabetically therein.
Scope and Contents
The papers comprise correspondence, subject files, photographs, and memorabilia documenting aspects of Robert Wilbar Wilson's student years at Yale, his military service, and post-war business endeavors.
Biographical / Historical
Robert Wilbar Wilson was born on August 25 or 26, 1893, in Harrisburg, Pennsylvania, the son of Edwin E. and E. Loretta Wilbar Wilson. He earned his B.A. degree from Yale in 1916. He joined the Army in May 1917, serving through 1922. He then entered sales promotion work in the pharmaceutical industry and rubber manufacturing. In June 1941, he rejoined the Army and was involved in planning the invasions of Normandy and Japan. Wilson was appointed deputy administrator of the Veterans Administration (VA) branch in Philadelphia on October 31, 1945, and later he became manager of the Philadelphia Regional Office of the VA. He retired from government service in 1953 and became a management consultant. He married Edith Miller in 1919. Wilson died in Tucson, Arizona, on February 13, 1975.
Wilson, Robert W. (Robert Wilbar), 1893-1975; Yale University. Alumni
- Inventory
  - Autobiographical material, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence
    - Austin, E., 1915 March (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Brewster, Kingman, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Thurmond, Strom, 1974 December (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Wall Street Journal, 1971 July-August (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Subject files
    - Employment, 1916-1917, 1931-1935 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Memorials and condolences, 1975 February-March (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Newpaper clipping, Philadelphia Inquirer Magazine, 1959 May 17 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Stopperless water bottle design, 1932 October-November (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - "World War I Experiences", Circa 1917-1922 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Scope and Contents
      Includes photographs and Army discharge papers.
    - World War II and post-World War II military service, 1943-1956 (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
    - Yale College
      - Daily themes, 1915, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - "Self-Help at Yale", 1912-1918 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Yale Bowl, photograph of spectators, Circa 1915 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Yale Class Day program, 1916 June 19 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Yale diploma, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Yale-Princeton Game, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 16)